Clayton J. Lewis

614 146th St. Apt. #4 New York, NY, 10031 775-233-7630 lewisclayton89@gmail.com

SUMMARY:

I'm a technical professional that takes pride in having versatile knowledge in various systems and workflows. I've proven to be consistent in fulfilling key projects to accurate completion in addition to making an influential contribution by applying my vast experience and incredible work ethic.

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

Spectrum News NY1 - New York, NY Media Ingest Editor (07/2019- Present)

Working with Dalet (MAM) software to record media by way of decoders and fiber feed lines in addition to the asset ingestion of video content from camera cards and third-party sources. Operating a Harris Router for delegated task such as quality control checks and distributing video content for Spectrum affiliates. Remotely coordinating live shows for shoot locations and IFB checks. Fulfilling auxiliary assignments such as segment replay cuts, video asset placement, archival restores and troubleshooting system malfunctions.

Meredith Corporation – New York, NY Video Ingest Technician (09/2018- 07/2019)

Preforming with Evolphin Zoom (MAM) software for video ingestion while coordinating the accurate metadata for specific assets for media archival storage. Distinguishing various video codecs for appropriate transcoding methods in addition to troubleshooting asset and system software failures. Working with camera cards, hard drives, video and studio exports while executing proper file transfer protocol for media asset organization. Effectively communicating with VAM, studio, and brand teams to maintain a successful media operation.

Adobe Stock Media – New York, NY Coordinator, Media Operations (02/2017- 08/2018)

Directly responsible for the coordination of media assets delivered from premium contributors and successfully distributing their content into feasible workloads for the creative team's online moderation process. Executing proper file transfer protocol, project setup, and asset storage through DF Studio (DAM) software. Preforming auxiliary duties such as FTP assisted uploads, metadata indexation, and media ingestion. Overlooking the shipping and receiving of contributor hard drives. Fulfilling various request regarding inventory reports, asset removals, file conversions, and troubleshooting issues. Clearly identifying system affairs such as

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND ATTRIBUTES:

Computer Programs and Software: MacOS, Windows, Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office, Google Drive Project Management Software: Jira, Trello, Wrike, WebEx, Slack, Programing Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Positive attitude with an enthused desire to learn.
- Powerful sense of urgency and detail in a professional work atmosphere.

software malfunctions, ingestion failures, and contributor account discrepancies.

• Passionate in providing excellence service to valued clients and customers.

EDUCATION:

State University of New York College at Buffalo:

Bachelor of Arts, Media Production- May 2014

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVIES:

- Software Engineer Intern for Neetos Inc. (2018-2019)
- Head Coach for Ice Hockey in Harlem program (2016- Present)
- Professional Line Cooking Experience (2013-2018)
- Buffalo State Bengals Men's NCAA Division III Hockey Team (2010-2014)